on today's video we're going to try and
fix this busted ninja creamy Deluxe for
the least amount of money
possible so I paid $20 Canadian for this
on Facebook Marketplace the seller said
it was broken and it's got a common from
what I can tell it's got a common
problem where the blade drops out uh and
doesn't stay attached to the lid so
there are a couple of things that this
didn't come with and there's a couple of
things that this had done to it so they
obviously sent it to ninja creamy as a
warranty repair and they determined that
it wasn't worth repairing so they cut
the power cable off and then sent it
back that's a common kind of practice
these days but we can get around that
easy enough it's just a power cable
before we talk about how we plan to
repair this let's take it out of the box
and actually see what the condition is
right so we have our
machine the cable is definitely been cut
off this is a pretty thin gauge power
cable now I've got a spare one had this
in the drawer for something else so we
can replace that if you're going to do
this make sure you replace a cable with
the same grade cable so if it's an 18
gauge then replace it with an 18 gauge
um don't start reducing the size of the
cable because it will catch fire so
handy little bcro tab so we don't we're
not going to reuse
this the actual condition of the machine
is pretty reasonable I mean it's dirty
so let's get
this and let's get in and see what we
have the
actual container housing is fine no
brakes again it's dirty
nothing really crazy going
on so it's in it's in pretty reasonable
condition it came with the useless
instruction manual came with a quick
start guide safy instructions so before
we get started I'm going to clean these
are notoriously difficult to clean there
are obviously you've got your latch here
which is the release mechanism for your
blade now that capsule under here gets
full of junk gets full of crap in the
relaxed position there is a hole just in
here and you can actually run hot water
through there whilst moving the actual
latch
itself and that will enable you to get
water in here and clean this so before
we get started I'm going to give this
machine a full clean and then we'll come
back and then the last thing to do is
just to take this out and I'm going to
run this under the warm tap and clean it
off and there is our cleaned machine
some things to note in the clean the
actual blade itself is very dirty or was
very very
dirty and that's the indication that
it's not been cleaned properly after
each event so I mean it's not difficult
to clean this blade is
in pretty poor condition but grabbing it
and turning it it doesn't turn on its
own which means the motor's good so what
we're going to do is just take a soft
sponge and get that around there you
don't really want lots of water going
down in that Gap but we're going to get
that in there and just give that a nice
clean and if there's something that you
can't remove get a little toothpick get
a little screwdriver anything like that
and we're just going to pick out any
little residue
couple of things we needed to buy before
progressing one is the
blade didn't come with this machine and
that is because when I looked at the
seller the blade was
damaged uh and I didn't want to P pay
$25 for that blade when I can pay $22 $2
for a brand new one which isn't damaged
straight from Amazon I'll put a link in
the description this is an excellent
blade works perfectly size perfectly so
so we we've got our new blade what we
really need to do is open up the machine
and get this power cable changed you're
going to need a T10 Torx
bit to get the bottom off
here and you're going to need to take
screws out from here all of these
locations to remove that we don't need
to take these out yet so the T10 Torx is
for the front screw and the two back
screws and the rest of the screws are
Philips head number two as you lift off
you have your release button down here
this just comes off there are two small
Springs I'll show you those in a second
which will fall out and that is these
this is your release switch for your
container and these are the Springs
these sit in here like this keep those
safe do not lose those so now that we've
got the bottom released we can see that
the cable
goes there's a cable cover inside and
that slides down the back here like so
and that just protects the cable inside
so we can remove that the actual power
cable now goes around here this is a
safety latch we need to undo this here
which is a Philips head number two and
that is an anti- strain lock so if you
were to pull the cable it won't pull the
cable out of the motor inside keep all
those washes safe and that is our base
weighted it's got our mechanism inside
there as well so we can put that aside
now what we need to do is get to the
actual motor itself with the machine
upside down we can see there are some
screw locations all the way around here
and we're going to need to we're going
to need to undo all of those and they
are all T10 torx
bits now with that done we can look at
removing the top case so to remove the
side panels to get access to the actual
PCB part of the controller what we need
to do is remove these little things here
you can either use a little pry plastic
pry or you can use a flathead
screwdriver and just gently put either
in between where those screws go and it
will just start to pop off like that do
the same the other
side and now we are starting to get
access to our ninja creamy we can see
the PCB inside we can see the motor we
can see the drive shaft here and we can
also see cables now obviously something
to check is the condition of the
components here we have
our power
modulator and if you pull the cable you
can
see there is our power cable so now what
we're going to do is we're just going to
protect our work toop and put that on
there like that because we obviously
this is the part we're going to replace
so we can see that it's here you'll be
able to feed that cable back
out like that we've got a brown and a
blue and these are just crimped together
we're going to replace these with
straight Spade connectors and get the
new cable on this is simply a case of
cutting
these so now what we're going to do is
just going to take the end off
here because we are going to put on our
new spay connectors and our protective
sleeves there we have our cable coming
up through
here to join the two existing power
cables and now we're going to just
gently pull that cable back
through the tube goes all the way down
there sits in that hole and these two
little lugs just push in over the top
like so and then that will keep your
cable inside these are your three lugs
at the back you're simply gently pushing
those in make sure that they line up and
then it will all snap back together
[Applause]
like I pointed out before our release
button has two Springs inside now what
we need to do is make sure that those
Springs stay inside you show you where
they go that goes on like that and that
goes on like that and our button goes in
this
orientation what we're simply going to
do is slide that over the top like that
over those two buttons because when we
press that that releases this little
latch here so that in place like that
and gently lift this up because we're
going to slide this over the top there's
a lot of space in there for that excess
cable we can just now just grab the
whole thing turn it
over let's um before we do that let's
first plug this in and see if we've got
power
with our new cable we've got power there
we go the install button is flashing and
that is just because we don't have this
fitted there's no blade in here we're
going to get to that any
second there we go install and then the
flashing power light because there's no
blade so the problem this was originally
diagnosed with is the very common
problem of the blade falling out
so when you lift your bowl
up the blade falls
out this is a super common problem and
there really is only one reason as to
why this
happens now if you're not sure if this
is a problem you have easy way is to
just take your Blade with your machine
turned
off put your blade up and spin it so
that it interacts with the with the
motor shaft if it doesn't stick to it if
it's not magnetized then your magnet
inside here has demagnetized the magnet
is
here is there that is your magnet in the
end there it's a very small magnet but
that is what is causing the problem why
these demagnetize so magnets demagnetize
under heat and not a lot of heat to be
fair we're talking small magnets here
we're talking 5 mm across 2 mm
that that's all that is and the heat is
generated by friction as this blade
spins down it is plummeting down through
a frozen mass that creates friction
which in turn creates heat which travels
up through this into that magnet and
over time demagnetizes it not a lot of
time either what causes more heat is the
bad recipes the solid blocks of ice that
people are trying to process in their
ninja cream creamies that's creating too
much heat and will demagnetize your
shaft magnet there there are two ways
around this you can either replace this
magnet and that is drill that out and
put a new one in or the method I like to
recommend people get a tiny little
magnet like this a tiny little magnet
that is 5 mm x 2 mm on Amazon super
cheap I mean I I think I got an entire
pack of 2 5x2 magnets along with L of
other sizes for about 12 Canadian dollar
and we are going to sit that in here so
as this is metal and that you're dealing
with a magnet it can be a bit fiddly
what I like to do is just take a small
pair of
tweezers and drop it in and then just
manipulate it and I'll show you in a
closeup so your magnet is sitting on the
bottom you won't be able to get it in
the center because of the way magnets
work but that is where it is as you saw
that took about 3 seconds to do and now
what we can do is just test that on
there and it's stuck all right the
magnet will not get pulled
off what we can do
is put that in there super easy quick
fix to your demagnetized ninja creamy
the way to stop it is to start making
better ice cream in there start making
and using proper recipes for balanced
ice cream any of my ice cream recipes
will will work in your Ninja creamy
they're balanced they're not solid
blocks of ice to be fair what causes
more problems is trying to Blitz hard
solid frozen fruit without anything else
in there because it's a recommendation
from creamy that you can do it you can't
you cannot do it you will break your
machine now they are going to replace it
if it's under warranty for free which is
excellent some people have actually had
up to three replaced for this because
they don't want to repair it all they do
is recommend you cut the cable off and
then they will send you a new one how
wasteful is that your machine is
absolutely fine it just needs that tiny
little magnet put inside if you want to
actually remove that magnet drill it out
and glue your new magnet in there that
is also fine the magnet is quite
difficult to remove so it's a bit of a
pain in the Jacks
but power on fully
working fully working we're going to
use full 2 minutes it doesn't really
make any difference what we're doing so
let's works perfectly let's get some ice
cream in there
blade perfectly still attached let's get
some scooped
up and there we go a ninja creamy Deluxe
fixed with a $2 magnet delicious
chocolate ice cream I will put a link in
the description for the ultimate
chocolate it's one of the best chocolate
ice creams you will ever eat don't throw
away your ninja creamy don't buy another
one don't even bother sending it back
for a replacement unless you know it's
seen some damage it's just super
wasteful and all they'll end up doing is
going into landfill which is the last
thing we need tiny little magnet fixes
your problem you're good to go let me
know if you want to see any more
maintenance tips tricks and information
on ninja creamies and their problems
don't forget to like And subscribe and I
will see you next time
[Music]